So I've been wanting to adapt my large collection of biology homework questions from kind of
a blackboard format to using library text adapt, which kind of uses like a web work
type format here, at least the way I've adapted them.
That seems to be probably the best format for working with biology problems.
But first I really needed a good sandbox tester for web work.
So I took the web work PG renderer, oh gosh, I thought I had the page up, but I do not.
I have too many repositories, apologies.
That's a web work.
That's there guys.
So yeah, so I took the web work PG renderer, which installs itself via Docker.
It's not the easiest thing to set up, I expanded it and modernized it.
And now I have this nice thing where I can drop in web work questions, render the question.
And if I want to go into debug mode, this is, you know, where all the nitty gritty nuts
and bolts generated HTML stuff exists, if you want to try and figure out what's going
wrong.
And that was really critical for me and especially using AI agents.
And it just kind of runs on my local computer, localhost 3000 here.
But since about November, last year, November, 2025, AI coding agents have really transformed
how I write computer code to tell you the truth, I really don't write computer code
much anymore, but I program all day.
It's vibe coding has really taken over.
And one of the deals is that chatgpt is just literally terrible at writing web work questions.
Let's let's do an example here.
Write a simple web work question asking my favorite color where the answer is blue.
All right, so I am on chatgpt 5.2 auto where it kind of sounds like, oh, yeah, sure, sure,
sure.
I can do that.
Oh, the last few times I did it actually just that show partial correct answers to one,
which means is there a partial correct like if I guess green, is that close to blue?
I don't know.
So let's see if it works.
So I'm going to copy this and then go back to my renderer here and up air and you can
actually go back and forth with chatgpt on this and eventually it'll convince you that
your renderer is broken and it is it is correct.
But for the most part chatgpt just cannot do it.
Clod code on the other hand actually is pretty successful.
But this is like the easiest question.
If I Google PGML multiple choice example, it's the number two hit is literally I'm sorry,
I guess it's not the number two hits.
I did this on DuckDuckGo.
So I know the number nine hit on DuckDuckGo.
So I have to scroll all the way down.
Number nine.
Oh, gosh, really, oh, here multiple choice of radio buttons.
This is literally the example question.
My favorite color is blue, right?
So it has this information on the internet to grab from, but it just gets confused with
all the Perl out there because web works like Perl, but not quite.
So what did I do?
So I mean, this is like the worst part of programming.
You're stuck debugging someone else's code, which is not what you want to do.
So what I've done is probably the best example is like Clod code, you know, it's codex works
okay.
It's a little bit slower.
Well, since I'm sticking to OpenAI, we'll stick with codex here.
So this is the codex app.
I have a web work codex forum here.
And I've written a skill, which is invoked with dollars on here called web work writer,
which basically gives it a whole bunch of documentation, it can use on how to write
good web work questions, because it's really needed, and it actually is able to connect
itself to the renderer to confirm that its code actually works.
It's obsessed with finding other files on my file system to use the cheat.
So we'll see if it gets up a thing, it's not the quickest thing I'm going to show a more
complicated example here that I launched 11 minutes ago, and Clod is still thinking about
it.
So.
All right, so here, favorite color blue, I think it was able to test it, we'll find out.
So let's go back to my renderer.
Bam, it's gotten a lot longer, and it's actually using pgml format, or it was kind of using
a hacky format before, it didn't quite work.
I really don't want to have to debug this some more, but I don't want to spend Oh, yeah,
so you can't use mice.
It should know that.
But yeah, who wants to sit here and debug code for the I'm gonna try and pretend.
But what if I want to write a more challenging question was my favorite color.
I've been teaching I was teaching my students last week, on isoelectric points of amino
acids, you know, it's kind of fancy curve, it's the point where there's no charge, and
they really when I posted this up on the slides, they're kind of I'm like, which one has the
neutral or what's the pi here, you know, and they're like, I don't know.
I got like 50 glazed eyes looking back at me and I'm like, this would be a great question
to add to adapt.
I do have a working copy of it.
But for example, here, I just kind of show random amino acid different charges, you should
be able to add a plus and a minus cancel out to say no net charge and then figure out what
the pi is based on a titration curve was my idea.
So I wrote up a prompt and, you know, fairly detailed as give this basically give this
whole prompt to chat GPT here, I want you to write a two part question from scratch
amino acid isoelectric points part one student selects hypothetical amino acid for three
pKa values.
This is the repo is empty, it's a fresh project.
But you know, the thing is, it has all these documents to consult because chat GPT wants
to use kind of its own random function, which is not how web work once right.
I was able to fire up codex earlier, I don't think I had to have I mean, it's not something
I could really do live in a video.
But basically, I gave it the prompt, I gave it a picture, I told it to load my skill.
I told it that all the documents it needs is in the skills, so please don't search my
hard drive, so it's, I have enough guidance to implement the problem now I've created
a new problem also change log entry the promise.
I'm now running the local renderer and I had some problems that do more up seeds problems
with firmware.
Yeah, I don't have to debug all that, let it do it.
Alright, so let's see how its final code came out.
So I'm going to open up the thing and then paste it back into my
render here.
I'm going to use my local renderer.
So it's kind of nice it properly tags the question now, with things it looks like what
strategy to use.
I don't know, can you even read that code early?
Does it work?
It does.
I find that the choice on the states is a little bit harder to read, I could use any
some color, I guess that's probably the correct one there.
And if we know choice two is the proper one, we can say the PI is probably between these
two values.
So somewhere around 3.2 should be the correct answer.
And I got 100%.
So it's that's one way it looks like cloud is finally getting back to me.
So you have to have patience when working with these AI things.
I launched this at 15 minutes ago, it came back and asked some questions about how I
wanted to do it.
It's not clear to me if it is, well, it hasn't given me a file, it still says tinkering.
But you know, it's better for it to kind of sit there and struggle getting the problem
correct than me sitting there to struggle, you can see it's kind of sending the problem
to the local renderer to verify.
So will it do a good job?
I don't know.
But I did try this earlier.
And it did finish eventually.
But I did delete its code, so kind of like that it was very similar kind of rendering
to the one that came out into my problem here.
The graph options available in web work are, I mean, they're not the greatest.
There's some classic ways using LaTeX and stuff.
And now it's asking for permission to run the renderer means that cloud is probably
going to take another 15 to 20 minutes to solve the question.
So I'm going to pop it up.
I know where it's stuck, should I help give it some guidance, tell it to read the skill
again.
I literally have a document on how to render HTML correctly.
It's complaining that I found the PG common pitfalls.
Oh, I actually have a file I can test now.
So let's see how Claude's version holds up to the codex version.
But renders fine.
Seems weird to have the state separate than the state selected, but the cool I'd recently
just told it to add color.
So it's figuring that out.
It did not read the documentation on how to add color to what did just post an update.
Oh, hey, we got blue questions in one place.
I know why it was like giving me like, here, let me put the net charge here.
And then it asked which one's net charge zero and it's like, yeah, no, it's what it renders
fine in WebRK 2.0.
This is PG 2.17.
And okay, it says CPC colors are there and verified.
Now the thing is, you get into a cycle of back and forth.
And so what I'm going to do is I can take a screenshot and share it as only the side
chains are colored, not back to fix that fairly quickly.
I think when I was saying red and blue things, so I can hit the dice here and it gives me
a different version of the problem.
See now here's the COOH version.
But the idea is I'm really into kind of randomizing my questions.
So the P AKA should vary between different versions.
So students just can't post them the check.
Of course, this is, you know, chat GPT probably can't write the question very well, but it
could probably solve this question fairly easy.
But that's not the point.
All right.
And I just thought I'd share kind of my system for writing WebRK code using AI agent.
Something you'd like to change about this?
All charged groups.
Sorry, I'm typing it there.
The video's over.
I'm just kind of, you'll see how it kind of I guess the question is, should we not color
COOH and color COO minus?
But if I look at the question now, you can see everything is rendered in color.
Yeah, I'd probably do the neutral ones in like a gray color or something like that.
So visually stands out more.
I need to learn a lot more about accessibility, but you know, I do like my color.
And I do try to avoid red greens.
You know, being in the Chicago area, I find the bears colors work pretty well if contrast
wise.
So right.
So anyway, that's one way to code a problem in WebRK.
You know, I did need to give it some guidance.
But all the tools are there to debug it at least.
So I need to know how to program.